<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Principles on One C</title>
    <link>https://www.onec.me/tags/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Principles on One C</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.onec.me/tags/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding meaning</title>
      <link>https://www.onec.me/blog/finding-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.onec.me/blog/finding-meaning/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to encourage others towards spiritual growth? At a recent board meeting, which included a fairly contentious issue, a number of friends and myself certainly did not encourage anyone towards spiritual growth. The root of the problem, as with many problems, lies with differences; differences of opinion, experience, and expectations. As a Unitarian Universalist congregation, we espouse the seven principles, which are as close to dogma as you&amp;rsquo;re likely to see in UUism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equity</title>
      <link>https://www.onec.me/blog/equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.onec.me/blog/equity/</guid>
      <description>The gospel of Matthew suggests that Christ&amp;rsquo;s heaven is an equal opportunity saver. That is, it is not a place where those who worked the hardest receive the best, or those who took and never gave suffer. The parable of the vineyard laborers more or less spells out a universal salvation message for those who would be willing to work, not for how much they work. And, as a parable, that means that those who come to find love and compassion late in life are no less entitled to salvation than anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>