<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Notes from the Castine Selectboard</title>
    <link>https://colinforcastine.com/categories/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Notes from the Castine Selectboard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://colinforcastine.com/categories/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/10/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/10/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Dear residents of Castine,
I am asking for your vote on November 7, 2017 for the privilage of becoming your next selectman.
Responsible governance does not appear out of thin air. It does not show up because we want it. It is the hard work of dedicated individuals who are passionate about their town.
As your next selectman:
I promise to be a passionate supporter of Castine and all our shared friends and neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you</title>
      <link>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/11/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/11/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Castine voters,
Thank you so much for your passionate support and most especially your vote at the polls this year! When you choose to run for public office, there is a vulnerability that you must reconcile before you get to work changing hearts and minds with your ideas. That reconciliation happened so quickly for me in this election primarily because this town is such a positive, supportive community.
Folk singer Greg Brown has a live album on which, in between two songs, he tells a story about living in a small town in the Upper Peninsula of Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selectpeople</title>
      <link>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/11/selectpeople/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/11/selectpeople/</guid>
      <description>Castiners, I want to make it clear that when I refer to my new position I will be using the term &amp;ldquo;selectperson.&amp;rdquo; That is intentional, and is not some crazy progressive ideology, it&amp;rsquo;s simply an acknowledgment that when you tack &amp;lsquo;-men&amp;rsquo; on the end of something it is passively exclusive.
The term originates from the idea that these &amp;ldquo;men&amp;rdquo; were &amp;ldquo;selected&amp;rdquo; to lead the town. Given that etymology, it only makes sense that if we hope to be exclusive to all humanity we should consider ourselves and any who would take up the position &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;selected&amp;rdquo; to lead the town.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>