<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Notes from the Castine Selectboard</title>
    <link>https://colinforcastine.com/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Notes from the Castine Selectboard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://colinforcastine.com/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media &amp; Communication</title>
      <link>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/12/social-media--communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colinforcastine.com/2017/12/social-media--communication/</guid>
      <description>A substantial part of the select board&amp;rsquo;s job is communicating effectively with the public. I will acknowledge before we get started here that not everyone is on social media (Facebook, Twitter, Snapchat, Instagram, etc.). Even more, many people don&amp;rsquo;t understand how they work. But for those who do use it, and understand at least at a basic level how it works, social media can be transformative.
More than a place to share funny pictures of cats with your friends, Facebook can be used to spread news of upcoming events, to receive RSVPs to those events, and to share ocmments ideas or documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow on the sidewalks</title>
      <link>https://colinforcastine.com/2018/01/snow-on-the-sidewalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colinforcastine.com/2018/01/snow-on-the-sidewalks/</guid>
      <description>We had an interesting dicsussion at our select board meeting this week about clearing snow from the sidewalks. The question asked was, why would we pay so much to put in nice sidewalks only to leave them essentially un-passable in the winter? Unfortunately the many of the board and municipal officer&amp;rsquo;s answers seemed unsatisfying to the public attendees of the meeting. Here&amp;rsquo;s my take, and recognize that this is just my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>