<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on a personal blog</title>
    <link>http://www.onec.me/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on a personal blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.onec.me/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Free and Responsible</title>
      <link>http://www.onec.me/post/free-and-responsible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.onec.me/post/free-and-responsible/</guid>
      <description>The way I was raised, certain people were simply wrong. If they didn&amp;rsquo;t share the same enthusiasm for science, they were incorrect. If they believed in a benevolent (or even malevolent) Christian god, they were wrong. There was very little gray in many of the positions that were espoused to me. One of the great aspects of humanity is that we are given the opportunity to raise our children with our values and beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equity</title>
      <link>http://www.onec.me/post/equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.onec.me/post/equity/</guid>
      <description>The gospel of Matthew suggests that Christ&amp;rsquo;s heaven is an equal opportunity saver. That is, it is not a place where those who worked the hardest receive the best, or those who took and never gave suffer. The parable of the vineyard laborers more or less spells out a universal salvation message for those who would be willing to work, not for how much they work. And, as a parable, that means that those who come to find love and compassion late in life are no less entitled to salvation than anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you like me?</title>
      <link>http://www.onec.me/post/are-you-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.onec.me/post/are-you-like-me/</guid>
      <description>One of the aspects of my faith that I have the most difficulty with is accepting other people regardless of where they are. As a human, I like to hang with people like me. This is understandable, as tribalism exists in the world as an artifact of the world we have lived in for the last 10,000 years.
And yet, UUism calls me to be accepting of others and to encourage others in their spiritual growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding meaning</title>
      <link>http://www.onec.me/post/finding-meaing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.onec.me/post/finding-meaing/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to encourage others towards spiritual growth? At a recent board meeting, which included a fairly contentious issue, a number of friends and myself certainly did not encourage anyone towards spiritual growth. The root of the problem, as with many problems, lies with differences; differences of opinion, experience, and expectations. As a Unitarian Universalist congregation, we espouse the seven principles, which are as close to dogma as you&amp;rsquo;re likely to see in UUism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are we grateful?</title>
      <link>http://www.onec.me/post/why-are-we-grateful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.onec.me/post/why-are-we-grateful/</guid>
      <description>I just finished the book The Righteous Mind by Jonathan Haidt and was struck by a line at the beginning of his acknowledgment section. Relaying what a graduate student once taught him he explains that we do not express gratitude to settle debts or sow the ground for favors. We give our gratitude out to make stronger relationships.
I was struck by what a simple, yet profound thought that was. Gratefulness is not a selfish tool we wield to get the upper hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>